Guide to the Paper Tiger Television Archive, ca. 1981-2014 MSS.276
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VII: Video recordings
  - Subseries A: PTTV - Broadcast Videotapes
    - CVL: Flava In Ya Ears - Master Edit, February, 21 1995 (Box 67, Media ID: 276.0220)
      A group of East Harlem High school students decide to make their own opinions heard through video after they are faced with massive city budget cuts to social services, the constant deluge of negative media coverage of inner city youth, and unresponsive mayor. In addition to providing a description and analysis of Mayor Guiliani and Govenor Pataki's cuts, this video shows the formation of the Community Voices League (CVL).
      1995 TRT: 28 minutes #262
    - Mumia Abu-Jamal: Giving Face to the Death Penalty - Master Deep Dish TV / Paper Tiger TV - An Emergency Broadcast, 1995 (Box 67, Media ID: 276.0221)
      Mumia Abu-Jamal: Giving a Face to the Death Penalty
      Who is Mumia Abu-Jamal and why has he been sentenced to death in the state of Pennsylvania?
      This tape looks at the personal history of Mumia Abu-Jamal, from his membership in the Black Panther Party, to his career as an award-winning journalist, and ending with his trial and sentencing in the death of a Philadelphia police officer. Interviews with his legal counsel, friends, and colleagues expose the criminal ways the prosecution attained his conviction and the concerted efforts on the part of the Fraternal Order of Police, the FBI, and the mainstream media to silence this prominent revolutionary journalist.This video raises critical questions about the rights of the accused, the inherent injustice of the U.S. judicial system when trying the poor and people of color, the function of the death penalty in the U.S., and our first amendment right to free speech.
      1995 TRT: 28 minutes #260
    - Falling Into the Trade Gap - mix - Original Edit, 1995 (Box 67, Media ID: 276.0222)
      Falling Into the Trade Gap
      This video introduces you to Leslie, a 16 year old Honduran girl, who makes sweaters for Liz Claiborne, earning 60¢ for each one completed. Her story is a common one among many girls in Central America. In countries across the region young women work 12 hour days making clothing for U.S. companies such as Liz Claiborne and the Gap. Charles Kernaghan of the National Labor Committee joins Paper Tiger in piecing together this tale of the reality behind these popular clothing manufacturers.
      1995 TRT: 28 minutes #263
    - Amy Goodman Takes Aim at the Contract on America, 1994 (Box 67, Media ID: 276.0223)
      Amy Goodman Takes Aim at the Contract on America
      This episode exposes the 1994 Contract With America, a document written by the US Republican Party detailing the actions the party promised to take if they became majority party in the United States House of Representatives. Amy Goodman tries to decipher: What lies behind the Republicans' Contract with America? What we find is more of a contract ON America, one that details a programmatic assault on civil liberties and women's rights. In response to the media representation around the Contract, and citizens' protests against it, comes the demand that media MUST stop being a vehicle for those in power. In order for the country to have a free media, it has reflect the democracy in this country, that is, the input of people who make up the majority of the population as opposed to the powerful minority.
      1994 TRT: 28 minutes #263b
    - America's Least Wanted, 1995 (Box 67, Media ID: 276.0224)
      America's Least Wanted
      "America's Least Wanted" takes a bite out of crime hysteria by exposing the media's fetish for high-profile crime stories. Robin Andersen takes you on a rare trip through the streets of corporate gangland, where "necktied hoodlums" get away with mass murder while a disinterested media and justice system turn a blind eye. Learn how prisons have become a high-stakes profit-making venture and why the Crime Bill is only the latest in ineffective and repressive anti-crime legislation.
      1995 TRT: 28 minutes #264
    - Narrowcasting: Technology and the Christian Right - Master, February 1996 (Box 67, Media ID: 276.0225)
      Narrowcasting: Technology and the Rise of the Christian Right
      This video explores the Christian Right's use of a constellation of communication technologies: satellite networks, cable TV, video production, and the internet to achieve their vision for the future, a dark void of democracy. With an in-depth analysis of this theocratic movement by authors Sara Diamond and Fred Clarkson, and activist/researchers Loretta Ross, Chip Berlet and the Rev. Barry Lynn, they point to how stealth campaigning, wedge issues, and "family values are used to navigate the program.
      1996 TRT: 28 minutes #265
    - ABC Survives, 5th Street Buried Alive, 1997 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0226)
      ABC NO RIO Survives, Fifth Street Buried Alive
      This is a live discussion with the squatters of 5th Street after the city demolition of their building. Speakers include Brad Will as well as squatter activists Shawnee Alexandri, Jason Fitzsimmons, Corinne Bordeaux, Steven Englander, Frank Morales, and Kurt Allerslev. In presenting their views, the squatters levy a powerful interrogation of not only Giuliani's clean up policies, but also the exorbitant Manhattan real estate prices that have made their style of life all the more necessary.
      1997 TRT: 28 minutes #269
    - Colombia and the Media: Illusions of the Drug War - Master, 1998 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0227)
      Colombia and the Media: Illusions of a Drug War
      PTTV in conjunction with
      The Colombia Media Project bring us an in-depth look at the mainstream media's misrepresentation of the political conflict in Colombia. In this presentation of Colombia's political situation, Mario A. Murillo locates the tragic global consequences of the US' "War on Drugs" in Colombia's rural communities. Murillo's presentation is spliced with Victoria Maldonado's interview with exiled Colombian journalist and human rights activist Richard Velez, who has been a vocal witness to his country's "Dirty War". Velez was forced to flee Colombia when he recorded army troops killing civilian protestors. This interview used Velez's story to reveal the paradoxical nature of US foreign policy in Colombia, which has allowed the Colombian government to perpetrate extreme violence and civil rights abuses all in the name of the US-led War on Drugs. Ironically, as Mario A. Murillo points out, the US media is equally complicit in obscuring this country's strife by figuring Colombia simply as "the Kingdom of Cocaine."
      1998 TRT: 28 minutes #274
    - Robert McChesney Takes On Media Globalization - Edit Master - 2 channel mono, 1997 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0228)
      Robert McChesney Takes on Media Globalization
      Robert McChesney explains the conglomeration of culture and information. According to McChesney, Murdoch to Microsoft are pushing their way to the front of the line, leaving the forces for democracy, diversity, and decentralization scrambling to catch up. He explains the impact of the new telecommunications laws on chances for fair and open media landscape, and where the next big battles are shaping up.
      1997 TRT: 28 minutes #267
    - Keep On Living- Master - from Mini-DV Master, 2002 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0229)
      Keep On Livin'
      Le Tigre, encapsulated by Kathleen Hanna, Johanna Fateman, and J.D. Samson, is a feminist electronic-punk band that has staged multi-media performance art within our live show. In collaboration with Le Tigre, Paper Tiger Television organized a group of G/B/L/TS/T/Q youth in New York to produce a three minute video for the song "Keep On Livin'". This visual layer will foreground conceptual and theoretical ideas that might otherwise be lost in the rock club settings where the band often perform.
      2002 TRT: 3 minutes #308
    - Market This!, 2003 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0230)
      Market This!: Queer Radicals Respond to Gay Assimilation
      MARKET THIS! is a documentary that explores the desire for radical politics and culture in the Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual, Two-Spirited and Transgender community. The documentary began in 1999 after the Queeruption gathering in New York City. During workshops and caucuses and through discussion and entertainment, participants came together to explore ways that this community can sustain and validate itself without supporting a system that actively exploits poor people, women, People of Color, g/b/l/TS/t people. This video takes the dialogue from Queeruption one step further. MARKET THIS! considers both the successes as well as the problems which resulted most visibly (and ironically) from a lack of involvement and presence of People of Color and Transgender people. While the gathering was an interactive platform for sharing and inspiring DIY (Do It Yourself) culture, it was, in many ways, a homogeneous White-dominated event.
      2003 TRT: 28 minutes #310
    - Re-Station The Union Address - Master, 2003 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0231)
      Restating the Union
      "Restating the Union Address" attempts to correct George Bush's 2003 State of the Union Adress, a speech that "dropped the ball in the fact-checking department". Featuring pop-ups correcting President George''s most obvious blunders, it also includes interviews with anti-war demonstrators in Manhattan, Washington D.C., and the Bronx. It is rounded out with a counter-military recruitment segment and a segment from the PTTV/Impact Coalition/Bronx Defenders production "War and the Economy" where High School students from the Bronx, Manhattan, and Brooklyn look at how the threat of war with Iraq would economically impact the communities of New York.
      2003 TRT: 28 minutes #311
    - War and the Economy - Master, 2002 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0232)
      War and the Economy
      Produced by high school youth from Manhattan, the Bronx, and Brooklyn in reaction to the financial stress felt in New York pre-dating the war in Iraq in 2003. In the search for the true opinions of New Yorkers on the war and local economy, the young producers conduct interviews in some of the diverse neighborhoods in New York City including Soho, Times Square, and in their neighborhoods in the Bronx. The production illuminates opinions on how the war would impact New York City ­ and has been used as an educational tool about the war with Iraq.
      2002 TRT: 7 minutes #312
    - Resisting the Empire - Master, 2003 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0233)
      Resisting the Empire
      Resisting the Empire was completed as a tool to critique the media's coverage and participation in the War in Iraq (Gulf War II). Resisting the Empire features interviews with organizers from DRUM, Peace Williamsburg, The Green Party, Corporate Lawyers Against the War, Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting, Colombia Social Justice, Labor against the War, Riot Grrls NYC, Nodutdol, High school students, a Long Island resident and father of 4, and other New York based organizations. The show looks at the history of US military involvement and foreign policy, the corporate media's coverage of the resistance against the war, techniques for illustrating military intervention on the major networks, and gives some instructions on how to get involved in your own community in activism for peace.
      2003 TRT: 28 minutes #316
    - Standing with Palestine - Master, May 5, 2004 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0234)
      Standing with Palestine
      "Standing with Palestine" looks at the growing movement in the United States in support of the Palestinian people and against the Israeli occupation of the West Bank and Gaza Strip. Through interviews with activists, the video shows how many Americans are no longer accepting the traditional views and official policies that have contributed to, if not caused, the worsening situation in the Middle East. These organizations are finding creative ways to be heard and to affect real change from a grassroots perspective. Groups highlighted include the ''International Solidarity Movement'', which seeks to bring attention to the Palestinian cause through direct action and confrontation of the Israeli army in the Occupied Territories, ''Jews Against the Occupation'', and ''Stop US Tax-funded Aid to Israel Now'' (SUSTAIN), which are finding creative ways to raise consciousness in the United States and force change in the US''s role in the Middle East. The video also includes interviews with activists on US campuses who are building a campaign, based on the Divestment campaigns in the 1980''s against Apartheid South Africa, to force Universities to withdraw their investments from companies that contribute to and support the Israeli Occupation.
      2004 TRT: 12 minutes #314
    - Homeless in Toronto - Master, 2003 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0235)
      Homeless in Toronto: Fighting Back
      Dee Dee Halleck and Rebecca Garrett help relate the struggles of the homeless in Toronto, Canada. The last two years have seen major confrontations as the population of people without shelter seek redress by squatting, protesting, live-ins in the municipal park and a militant march on the Canadian parliament. Although continually met with violence and harassment, they fight back for the right to affordable housing. This program features John Clark, who had been charged with sedition against the nation for his actions as a leader of OCAP, the Ontario Coalition Against Poverty. Clark is an inspirational leader whose tactics have influenced homeless organizing from Delhi to Capetown. His persecution by the Canadian government is used as an example of the attempts to silence international radical opposition. This production was made by students at OISE (Ontario Institute for Studies in Education) and OCAD (Ontario College of Art and Design.)
      2003 TRT: 28 minutes #315
    - 20th Anniversary Compilation 2001 - Master - made from Mini-DV Master (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0236)
      20th Anniversary Compilation: Sampling 20 Years
      Paper Tiger looks back at its productions from "Herb Schiller Reads the New York Times" and "Elayne Rapping on Soap Operas" as well as more recent productions such as "Military Myths" and "Rock, Paper, Missiles". This compilation of short clips is a way to see the strength of the collective's contribution to Independent Media and to providing alternative information resources.
      2001 TRT: 10 minutes #317
    - Hollywood Victory: Delusions of a Maverick President - Master, 2003 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0237)
      Hollywood Victory: Delusions of a Maverick President
      Produced in reaction to George Bush Jr's landing on the USS Lincoln to declare an "end to physical combat" in Iraq in June 2003, Hollywood Victory is a culture Jamm to offer an alternate spin to what the corporate media dishes out.
      2003 TRT: 3 minutes #318
    - Class Dismissed - Master - made from Mini-DV Master, 2004 (Box 68, Media ID: 276.0238)
      Class Dismissed
      Class Dismissed provides a critical look at how U.S. history is taught in high school, at the myths that reduce the complexity of history into simple soundbites, and the information that never seems to make it onto the textbook pages.This video takes a beginning step by looking at the textbook industry, standardized testing, the lack of race and class analysis in textbooks, and the teacher's role in introducing a range of perspectives into the classroom. Featuring authors Howard Zinn (A People's History of the United States) and James Loewen (Lies My Teacher Told Me), New York public high school students, textbook industry insiders, and teachers.
      2004 TRT: 28 minutes #320
    - #286 - Homecoming Queens, Undated; cuid39073 (Box 82, Vhs ID: 276.0455)
      Original format: VHS
  - Subseries B: PTTV - Non-broadcast Videotapes
    Subseries B: Non-Broadcast Videotapes contains production elements, unedited footage, production trailers, and other assorted production elements and/or preservation masters.
    - Herb Schiller on the New York Times #1 - Steering Mechanism of the Ruling Class, June 20, 2004 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0239)
      Original format: Digital Betacam Remaster of 3/4" Original
      Currently unavailable.
    - #2 Herb Schiller Reads the New York Times, June 20, 2004 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0240)
    - Herb Schiller Reads the New York Times #3 - The Sunday Times - 712 Pages of Waste, June 20, 2004 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0241)
    - #4 Herb Schiller Reads the New York Times, June 20, 2004 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0242)
    - Schiller on Trash TV / Dan Rabbit: From Woodstock to Tiananmen (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0243)
      Original format: Betacam SP
    - Kunstler on Constitution / Schiller on NYT #2, October 24, 1990 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0244)
    - #22 Brian Winston - TV News / Schiller 3 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0245)
    - #42 Richie Perez Reads Fort Apapche / #8 Teresa Costa Reads Biker Lifestyle, October 3, 1991 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0246)
    - #47 Bill Boddy Reads the 1934 / Communications Act / #21 Brian Winston Reads TV Guide, August 28, 1991 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0247)
    - Nolan Bowie Reads About Privacy / Animals in the Mass Media / new dubmaster, October 13, 1990 (Box 69, Media ID: 276.0248)
    - #92 Varda Burstyn Reads Playboy / #61 Rereading the Dragon, August 13, 1991 (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0249)
    - #129 Kathleen Hulser Debones the Poulty Industry: It Takes a Tough Ad Agency to Make a Tender Chicken - mixed audio / #181 Going for the Green: Bill Weinberg Looks at the Marketing of Earth Day & Environmentalism (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0250)
    - Joan Does Dynasty / Sock Ads, November 12, 1190 (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0251)
      Original format: Betacam SP, dubbed from 3/4" edit masters
    - How History Was Wounded /Soaps (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0252)
    - Alex Cockburn Reads the Washington Post / Muriel Dimen Reads Cosmo, 1992 (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0253)
    - Judith Mayne Reads Soap Mags; Columbus, Ohio - edited master (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0254)
    - Neil Smith USA Today: Myths and Realities - Live Satelite Uplink - distribution master, January 7, 1992 (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0255)
    - Transformer AIDS with Bob Kinney / Felt Evidence, April 17, 1991 (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0256)
    - Black Media / Martha Rosler Reads Vogue, March 3, 1992 (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0257)
    - Torn Between Colors / The Weekly Mail / mixed, new dubmaster (Box 70, Media ID: 276.0258)
    - Paper Tiger TV in Austin, Texas, Tape #1 - The Bulk of the Show - up to 306=SIN (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0259)
    - On Location with Paper Tiger Television, July 26, 1986 (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0260)
    - College Students Read College Dailies - Master, off-air (unedited), January 28, 1987 (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0261)
    - Flo Kennedy on Access - master original (uncut), June 16, 1989 (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0262)
    - Special Recording off SATCOM 3R, Transponder 7, 3:00pm - 4:00pm, July 12, 1988 (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0263)
    - Youth 92 - edited master (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0264)
    - Getting a Grip on Access (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0265)
    - Omni - edited master - Intro (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0266)
    - Joans Omni Show (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0267)
    - Paper Tiger Newstand - dub #1 - Install & Replace, 1991 (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0268)
    - Martha Wallner - Work Sample (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0269)
    - Quote...Unquote / Cyberspace (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0270)
    - Mark Rotenberg - Computer Professionals for Social Responsibility (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0271)
    - Dirk Koning - Tony Riddle - Cyberspace, 1993 (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0272)
    - Cyberspace 2600 Interview and NYNEX Pt. 2 last 7 minutes (Box 71, Media ID: 276.0273)
    - Cyberspace / Willamina Cooke (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0274)
    - SWOP (Southwest Organizing Project) & Las Vegas Strike - edit without titles (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0275)
    - Cyberspace NYNEX Part 1 - dub from Hi-8 Master (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0276)
    - COOP Doc - General meeting - Cam 1, Tape 1 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0277)
    - 1st Access Meeting - camera 2, part 1- Diana Agosta, Karen Rogoff, Judy Escolono, Sean Caulomusto, June 13, 1989 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0278)
    - 2nd Access Meeting - camera 1, part 1 - Lilian Jimenez, Dee Dee Halleck, Vicky Gholson, June 20, 1989 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0279)
    - 1st Access Meeting - camera 1, part 1 - Dianna Agosta, Karen Rogoff, Judy Escolona, Sean Coulomusto (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0280)
    - 1st Access Meeting - camera 1, part 2 - Dianna Agosta, Karen Rogoff, Judy Escolona, Sean Coulomusto, June 13, 1989 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0281)
    - Flo Kennedy on Access - Edit Master, June 20, 1989 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0282)
    - TV Turn On - dub (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0283)
    - Access Demo - Time-Life Headquarters #1 - David Shulman, May 2, 1990 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0284)
    - Preparing props for demo at Avenue D - Time Warner demo - #1 - shot by Martha Wallner on Hi-8, 1 of 2 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0285)
    - Time Warner demo #2 - shot by Martha Wallner (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0286)
    - Public Access Demo (Ilona's Cam), May 2 (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0287)
    - Hill & Knowlton - show source tape (Box 72, Media ID: 276.0288)
    - Hill & Knowlton - show roll-ins - demo & end credits (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0289)
    - Ladies of the Lake - Heather Connor, Armin Heurich, Jody Laford, Chris Hill, Hallwalss, Susan Clements (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0290)
    - 1988 NYSCOA Sampler (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0291)
    - #62 1988 FIVF-Benton Sampler - Robin Andersen, New York Three, Robbie Conal, Martha Rosler (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0292)
      Original format: 3/4" U-matic S
    - NYSCA Sampler 1989 (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0293)
    - Access Orbit PSA 1:00, Version 1 = FSTV dish network schedule, Version 2 = Public access TV announcement, October 2000 (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0294)
    - Sampler of 5 Shows (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0295)
    - Access Orbit PSA 1:00, Version 1 = FSTV, Version 2 = General public access, November 5, 2000 (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0296)
    - Sample #5 - Flo, Romance Novels, Subway Ads, Playboy, Mary's tape (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0297)
    - 1987 Sampler - Master edit (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0298)
    - 1981-1982 Sampler #2 - Master (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0299)
    - NYSCA 1991 Sampler (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0300)
    - Joey's Portrait (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0301)
    - Paper Tiger Trailer (30 seconds), 2003 (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0302)
    - Access Orbit PSA (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0303)
    - Graphics - Middle East Show, September 1990 (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0304)
    - Andrea PSA Music (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0305)
    - NYSCA 1991 Sampler - Master (Box 73, Media ID: 276.0306)
    - Michele Mattelant #1 (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0307)
    - Mattelant Cutaways - Movies, Les Femme De Pinodret (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0308)
    - TV Turn On! - Credits, NYCCRM at City Hall, statements (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0309)
    - Public Access Demo (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0310)
    - Middle East Conference - Cooper Union - Master edit (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0311)
    - Robin Andersen Exposes the Real Deal: The CIA-Contra-Cocaine-Connection, Saying No to Drugs; single camera on Robin A., November 1987 (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0312)
    - Robin Andersen Exposes the Real Deal: The CIA-Contra-Cocaine-Connection, Saying No to Drugs - Master (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0313)
    - Nic. Iran/Contra (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0314)
    - Owego; PTTV - Tune in next week & address change; Iran - Poet; Peirnter - Bloshes, March 5, 1989 (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0315)
    - Owego - Iran & scroll of PTTV tapes (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0316)
    - Nicaragua, Iran Contra (Box 74, Media ID: 276.0317)